各位 我快搞定座位安排了
Guys, I am nailing my seating chart.
能别把我排在卢克旁边吗
Can you not put me near Luke?
我受不了他嚼东西的声音
I can't with the chewing.
你就是个被宠坏的城市小孩
You are a spoiled city kid.
我小时候直到11岁才能跟人类坐一桌
I was 11 before I got to sit at the people table.
小卡 我都问你十次了
Cam. Cam, I've asked you 10 times.
你怎么还没给我发
Why haven't you sent me our itinerary
去你父母家的行程安排
for your trip to your parents' house?
最近有点忙
Been a little busy.
内容是你 我还有莉莉上圣诞老人的电臀舞课
of you, me, and Lily dancing in Santa's Twerkshop.
瞧瞧我们的屁股啊
Look at our butts.
圣诞快乐
Merry Christmas!
-圣诞快乐啊 -大家好啊
- Merry Christmas. - Hello.
谁给我拿杯酒啊
So, who's going to get me a drink?
老娘不用再喂母乳了
Mama's done breast-feeding.
这对"奶宝"又属于我自己了
These babies are all mine again,
我准备把它们里面灌满酒
and I'm ready to fill 'em up with wine.
人体构造的原理不是这样的
Well, not how the human body works,
但我很为你开心
but I'm very happy for you.
-我怀念过去的海莉 -我也是
- I've missed Old Haley! - Me too.
话说 你能把我和宝宝跟海莉隔得远一点吗
Oh, hey, can you move Haley away from me and the twins?
我送她的礼物就是让她今晚摆脱当妈的职责 所以...
My present to her is the night off from Mommy duties, so...
好吧 我真希望你能早点跟我说
Okay, well, I would've appreciated a little heads-up,
但这是份贴心的礼物 所以...
but it's a thoughtful gift, so...
也是免费的 这是大好事
It's also free, which is helpful
因为我夏天时忘记银行卡密码了
because I forgot my ATM pin last summer.
我有没有对你提过我最爱的四个数字
Any chance I ever mentioned my four favorite numbers to you?
没有
No.
别 千万别把我和歌洛莉亚排在一起
Oh, no. Please move me away from Gloria.
会很尴尬的
It'll be weird.
歌洛莉亚最近在我爸手下工作
Gloria's been working for my dad.
他那么悉心地指导她 但是那天
He totally mentored her, and then the other day,
我却抓到她去我爸的竞争对手那里面试
I caught her interviewing with his competitors.
话说 如果我真加入你们
So, if I come on board,
我需要把发型改成跟你们一样的吗
do I have to change my hairstyle?
-可以商量这事 -这算是我们的特色风格
- We'll talk about it. - It's kind of our thing.
给你这个聪明人提个醒
Word to the wise --
我就像是马修·麦康纳最近的五部电影
I'm like the last five Matthew McConaughey movies.
你从没看过我
You never saw me.
好吧
Fine.
圣诞快乐
Merry Christmas!
你们好啊
Hello.
圣诞餐桌就该这样才对嘛
Now, this is what a Christmas table should look like.
无意冒犯 亲爱的
No offense, honey.
我也喜欢你搞的"谁他妈在乎"风格的圣诞餐桌
I also love your whole "who cares" approach.
小卡
Cam?
我不能坐在爸爸旁边
I can't sit next to Dad.
我觉得他会叫我去他傻兮兮的狗窝公司工作
I think he's gonna ask me to work for his stupid dog bed company.
克莱尔
Claire!
怎么了
What?!
我不能在圣诞节让他心碎啊
I can't break his heart on Christmas.
你也知道节日会让他有爱又脆弱
You know how the holiday makes him so sweet and vulnerable.
我讨厌这傻逼围巾
I hate this damn scarf!
我看着跟女演员安杰丽卡·休斯顿一样
I look like Anjelica Huston!
是小卡买的 你给我戴着
Cam bought it! You wear it!
好爱这围巾哦 我感觉自己像个电影明星
Love the scarf! I feel like a movie star!
小卡 把我安排在克莱尔旁边好吗
Cam, put me next to Claire, okay?
我有事要跟她谈
I want to talk to her about something.
你终于来了
There she is!
我迫不及待要把礼物送给你了
I can't wait to give you your gift.
要现在打开吗 现在打开吧
Should we open it now? Let's open it now.
天啊 天啊
Oh, my God! Oh, my God!
你看懂了吗
You get it?
2020的远见
2020 vision.
是个双关啊
It works two ways.
你会出现在超多公交站长椅上
You are gonna be on so many bus benches.
但不是像以前你没嫁给杰时
And in a different way than when you had to go somewhere
出门都要等公交那种方式
before you married Jay.
天啊 爸 你对你的员工可真宠爱
Wow. Dad, that is a lovely gesture.
谢谢你 艾丽克斯
Thank you, Alex.
你总是知道什么该说 什么不该说
You always know what to say and what not to say.
菲尔 你太赞了
Phil, you're amazing.
我觉得这挺讽刺的
Which is ironic, I think,
因为你儿子可能是个反社会者
because your son might be a sociopath.
等等 这是怎么回事
Wait. W-What's all this, then?
你何不问问他呢
Why don't you ask him?
卢克 发生什么事了
Luke, what happened?
我来告诉你们发生了什么
I will tell you what happened.
他不但没有帮曼尼追回雪莉
Instead of helping Manny get Sherry back,
还将她抢为己有
he stole her for himself!
是真的 雪莉和我是一对了
It's true. Sherry and I are a thing.
-什么 -天啊 哇
- What?! -Oh, my God. Wow.
小卡 把曼尼划掉
Cam, take Manny off.
他不来了
He's not coming.
好了 大家随便坐吧
Okay, fine. Everybody just sit wherever they want,
就跟一帮流浪汉围着篝火乱坐一样
like a bunch of hobos around a barrel fire.
卢克 你怎么能做出这种事
Luke, how could you do this?
而且还是对曼尼下黑手
And to Manny, of all people?
我很内疚 但我跟雪莉的火花...
I feel bad, but this thing with Sherry is...
很特别
special.
这不是我平时的胡乱勾搭那种
This isn't my usual hit it and quit it.
-真"有魅力" -这话真刺耳
- Charming. - That's rough on the ears.
再说 雪莉根本不想跟曼尼在一起
Plus, Sherry doesn't want to be with Manny,
我们真的很来电
and we really connect.
我...
Well, I --
我觉得如果你真的那么在乎她...
I guess if you really care about her that much --
我是的
I do.
她聪明又很酷
She's smart and cool,
而且 她总是能逗我开心
and, man, does she make me laugh.
我懂
I get it.
没有比幽默的女人更性感的了
Nothing sexier than a funny woman.
或是井井有条的女人
Or an organized one.
你和小卡之间是怎么回事
So, what's up with you and Cam?
我察觉到紧张的氛围
I'm sensing tension.
我才没察觉到什么紧张的氛围
I didn't sense any tension.
我只是想听一些狗血八卦
I was just looking for some drama
我想着基佬门前多八卦是必然的
and figured it was a safe bet.
的确有点紧张的氛围
There is tension!
听着 首先
Okay, so, first of all,
他对于这顿晚餐有点过分关注
he's being extra crazy about this dinner.
但是你再听听这个
But now get this --
每年圣诞节 我都会抱怨
every Christmas, I complain about
要跟他一起回他老家 见他的家人
having to go home with him to -- to see his family,
但是今年 他说我不想去可以不用去
and this year, he said I don't have to go.
他对此完全没意见
And he was totally cool about it.
不妙 超级可疑
Oh, no. Super fishy.
所以你翻他的行李没有找到任何线索吗
So, you didn't find any clues when you went through his luggage?
我 没翻他的行李啊
I...didn't go through his luggage.
你简直像是希望你的婚姻破裂一样
It's like you want your marriage to fall apart.
跟我来
Come on.
我们要怎么解决卢克和曼尼之间的矛盾
What are we gonna do about Luke and Manny?
什么都不做
Nothing.
我最怕的就是争端升级 跟歌洛莉亚开启大战
The last thing I want is to get into a whole thing with Gloria.
亲爱的 有空吗
Hey, hon, got a minute?
最怕的是这个
Second to last.
抱歉 爸 我要去跟歌洛莉亚开启世界大战了
Sorry, Dad! I gotta get into a whole thing with Gloria.
没人可以开启任何大战
Or nobody gets into anything with anybody
我们要过个圆满的圣诞节
and we have a storybook Christmas.
要吃个迷你芝士球吗
How about a mini cheeseball?
卢克会跟雪莉分手吗
Is Luke going to break up with Sherry?
歌洛莉亚 我很抱歉曼尼这么伤心难过
Gloria, I am sorry that Manny is so upset,
但卢克的感情是真挚的
but Luke's feelings are sincere.
他已经非常自责了
He's already beating himself up.
求你了 别生他的气
Please, don't be mad at him.
你说得对 我不应该生卢克的气
You're right. I shouldn't be mad at Luke.
又不是他把自己养大的
He didn't raise himself.
重新说一次
One more time?
根据你过去的故事
Based on the stories from your past,
你很少会放弃享受肉体的快感
you've rarely denied yourself the pleasures of the flesh.
好了 暂...
Okay! Time --
-暂停 双方队伍请暂停 -小卡 小卡
- Time out! Time out! - Cam? Cam!
你怎么会有一张去密苏里州的头等舱机票
Why do you have a first-class ticket to Missouri?
先别问这个 你为什么翻我的行李箱
Okay, not now. And why are you digging through my suitcase?
老爸
Hey, Dad?
你就任由你老婆
Are you just gonna stand there
叫我荡妇吗
while your wife calls me a tramp?
我感觉现在加入讨论风险很大
I feel this is a risky time to weigh in.
同意 不要再吵了
Agreed. No more fighting.
我们都来享用芝士球吧
Let's just all enjoy a cheeseball!
这是我奶奶有百年历史的食谱
It's my grandma's 100-year-old recipe,
只是我用辣椒取代了可卡因
except I use cayenne pepper instead of cocaine.
不好意思 歌洛莉亚
I'm sorry, Gloria.
我不准任何人说我老婆放荡
No one calls my wife loose.
在她风华正茂时 是否享受过
In her day, did she enjoy
一些男人的陪伴 当然
the company of a few men? Sure.
是不是我们每次出门
Is it hard to leave the house
十有八九会撞见她的前任
without running into one of her ex-lovers?
看我们在哪个城市了
Depends on what city we're in.
你排比完了吗
Do you have an end to this?
她的身体她作主
Her body, her choices,
在这美丽星球上到处留情又如何
all over this beautiful planet!
-能不能说回头等舱机票的事 -是啊
- Can we get back to the first-class ticket thing? - Yeah. Yeah.
你想隐瞒什么呢
What are we hiding?
我不知道这事跟你有毛线关系
Okay, I'm not sure what you have to do with this,
但机票是我爸妈买给我的
but my parents bought me that ticket.
你爸妈
Your parents?
他们可是觉得放颗薄荷糖
The people whose idea of fancy
进杜松子酒里就够高档的土老帽
is dropping a Certs into a jar of schnapps?
我告诉你 奶奶的薄荷糖火箭
I'll have you know that Grandma's Mint Rockets
在州长官邸里可是广受欢迎呢
are the cocktail of choice at the governor's mansion.
你太娇生惯养曼尼了
You coddle Manny.
他早该放下雪莉了
He should already be over Sherry.
但我想让男孩子和妈同睡到15岁
But I guess that's what happens when you let a kid
就会有这种结果
sleep in your bed till he's...15.
我们为什么要讨论曼尼呢
Why are we talking about Manny, anyway,
这明摆着是菲尔的错啊
when this is clearly Phil's fault?
-什么 -什么
- What? - What?!
你显然没有
Well, I mean, you obviously
教卢克绅士守则
didn't teach Luke about the gentlemen's code.
我当然教了
I did so!
永远不要让别人的击掌尴尬停在半空
Never leave a high-five hanging,
如果你拍对方的背 那拥抱多紧都没问题
no hug is too tight if you slap the guy's back --
应该是朋友妻不可戏
It's never steal a broad from a friend,
绝对别让他留胡子
never let him grow a mustache
除非他的职业是有权威的应急人员
unless they're a first responder.
老爸 风大你也不怕闪了舌头
Okay. That is some high horse you're on there, Dad.
竟敢指责菲尔是失职的父亲
Accusing Phil of dropping the parenting ball?
开撕了
Here we go.
说出两个我小时候的朋友
Name two of my friends growing up.
刻薄的那个和体重超标那个
The mean one and the heavy one.
提醒一下各位 曼尼来了
Hey, just a heads-up -- Manny's here.
什么
What?
那表明他有多么勇敢
That shows how brave he is.
不过我们聊点别的话题吧
Eh, but let's talk about something else.
他最不希望的就是我们小题大做
The last thing he wants is to make all this a big deal.
大家好
Hello, all.
原谅我穿了阴沉忧丧气的袍子
Forgive my somber drapings,
但就像契诃夫《海鸥》里的玛莎一样
but like Masha in Chekhov's "The Seagull,"
我正在哀悼我的人生
I am in mourning for my life.
别担心 我不想惹事
And don't worry. I don't want any trouble.
今天我不是主角 家人团聚才是重点
Today is not about me. It's about family.
我们一家人
Our family.
还有我们分享的深刻深厚的爱
And the deep, profound love we share.
老天 这番话俗到爆
Man, that's cheesy.
或许吧 但这是我的真实感受
Maybe, but it's how I feel.
谢谢你曼尼 提醒了我们所有人什么最重要
Thank you, Manny, for reminding us all what's important
以及今年应该是我们最难忘的圣诞节
and how this should be the most memorable Christmas.
曼尼 你想喝香槟鸡尾酒吗
Manny, would you care for a champagne cocktail?
有劳了 我的确很喜欢香槟
Please. I do love champagne.
也许等我转过身去时
And maybe when I turn my back,
卢克可以把舌头伸入杯子里
Luke can put his tongue all over it.
全都好痛啊
Everything hurts!
卢克 我想你该走了
Luke, I think you should go.
不 他哪都不会去
No. He is not going anywhere.
每家都有一个坏胚子 需要被赶出去
Every family has a bad seed that needs to be cast out
这样他们才能浪子回头
so that they can find their way back.
我本来以为我们家的坏胚子会是海莉
I thought that ours was going to be Haley,
但意外怀孕
but an accidental pregnancy
拯救了她 没有走上堕落的人生
saved her from a life of degradation.
干嘛夸人家
Aww!
谁都不用离开
W-- Nobody has to leave.
我能和我爱的人们共度一个夜晚
I can spend one evening with the people I love
我也能忍受
and a shifty lecher
多一个戴着涂满蛋黄酱的浴帽睡觉的奸诈淫棍
who sleeps in a shower cap filled with mayonnaise.
那能让我的头发光泽靓丽
It gives me my sheen.
而且我让你别说出去了 你个怨夫
And I told you that in confidence, you hump!
好了 都给我闭嘴
Okay! Knock it off!
该用农场的裁决方式来解决了
It is time for some farm justice.
在我老家 如果同时有两头公牛想当老大
Back home, when we have two alpha bulls,
我们就把它们关进围栏里 决斗定胜负
we lock 'em in a pen and let them fight it out.
这是曼尼和卢克之间要解决的问题
This is between Manny and Luke.
快 走啊 哞 走啊
Come on! Let's go. Hyah! Hyah!
你们自便享用姜饼人哦
Oh, and help yourself to a gingerbread person.
都是无麸质无性别的
They're both gluten and gender free.
好贴心
Ohh!
好可爱哦
Oh. Isn't they a cutie?
没解决之前 不许出房门
Do not come out of this room until this is settled.
我对公牛说的 我现在也对你们说 先生们
I will tell you what I tell the bulls, gentlemen --
我爱你们俩
I love you both,
但别让我后悔没阉了你们
but don't make me regret letting you keep your testicles.
好 出拳揍我吧
Okay. Punch me.
我知道听起来很疯狂 但我觉得...
I know it sounds crazy, but I think --
漂亮
Amazing!
你居然真的动手
I can't believe you did that!
我也没料到 但告诉你 这并没让我好受一些
Me neither. And it didn't make me feel better, by the way.
要不试试踢他 或是戳他眼睛
Maybe kick him or jab him in the eye.
曼尼 对不起
Manny, I'm sorry.
我也希望是别的女孩
I wish it were someone else,
但我真的很在乎雪莉
but I really do care about Sherry.
我入睡前想着她
I go to sleep thinking about her.
醒来也想着她
I wake up thinking about her.
我一看到她 就好像
When I see her, it's like...
我的心也跟着笑了
my heart is smiling.
我还以为这个家里的娘炮指数已经封顶了呢
Wow. I didn't think this house could get any gayer.
我也很在乎她 我希望她幸福
Well, I care about her, too, and I want her to be happy.
所以
So...
一定要告诉她你的感情
make sure she knows how you feel.
她这种女孩需要听到那些
She's the kind of girl who needs to hear that.
我不知道 我不擅长这种事
I don't know. I'm not good at that stuff.
我还是装出高冷样子好了
I'm better off just playing it cool.
不敢相信我会这么说
Can't believe I'm saying this...
但我能帮你
but I can help.
我说 你打字
I'll talk, you type.
你对我这么好 是想让我更内"久"吗
Are you being nice to make me feel worser?
文盲 我说我打吧
Okay, I'll talk and type.
宝贝 你在这啊
Honey, there you are!
我一直想跟你说...
I've been wanting to talk to you about something --
你打出的那记个人史上最精彩的高尔夫吗
About the greatest golf shot you ever made?
-是哪一球来着 -老天
- What was that? - Oh, man.
在里维埃拉的第十洞
10th hole at Riviera.
-我当时面临两个选择 -是吗
- I had a decision to make. - Yeah?
我可以选左边 避开障碍 或是...
I could go left and stay out of trouble or --
做不到 是菲尔在叫我吗
Can't do it. Is Phil calling me?
在你走之前 我有个工作机会
Listen, before you run, I have a professional opportunity
-想让你考虑... -我也想听你说
- I'd like you to think -- - I-I'd love to hear it.
但我觉得有点闷 我出去喘口气
J-- I'm just a little stuffy. Let me get some air.
你知道吗
Are you aware that there are
全世界的狗加起来是意大利人口的15倍
15 times more dogs in the world than Italians?
感觉有点冒犯人 不确定为什么
Feels offensive. Not sure why.
我们是不是该跟其他人聊聊
Should we be mingling?
听着 我不会长篇大论
Listen. I'm not gonna do a big spiel.
只需告诉你 科学表明
Suffice to say that science has shown us
有一只精力充沛的狗狗 比起上大学
that having a well-rested dog improves our earning potential
更能提高我们的收入潜力
more than attending college.
爸爸 现在能陪我玩卡车吗
Dad? Can we play with my trucks now?
再等我几分钟 好吗
Give me a couple of minutes, buddy, okay?
因为我正在和斯黛拉狗床的新副总裁说话
'Cause I'm talking to the new VP of Dog Beds by Stella.
克莱尔
Claire?
你觉得小卡的父母真的
Do you really think that Cam's parents
给他买头等舱机票吗
bought him a first-class ticket?
他们不是很穷吗
Aren't they poor?
他们吃的植物动物
Don't they, like, eat plants and animals
不都是院子里捡的吗
they find in their yard?
他们是农民 是的
They're farmers, yes.
我们得继续深挖
We gotta dig deeper.
去拿小卡的手机 查他短信
Get Cam's phone. Check his texts.
那就侵犯他的隐私了
That's an invasion of his privacy.
再说 我都不知道他的密码
Plus, I don't even know his passcode.
刷脸就能开机
Well, I just need his face.
我总趁迪兰睡觉时查他手机
I break into Dylan's phone all the time while he's sleeping.
查了也白查
Not that I need to.
他只知道搜索水上乐园
All he does is Google water parks.
小卡舅舅
Uncle Cam!
我的手机落在车上了
I forgot my phone in my car,
我想跟我最爱的舅舅在漂亮的圣诞晚餐前
and I want to take a Boomerang of me and my favorite uncle
一起录个表情包
at his gorgeous Christmas dinner.
-我能用你的手机吗 -我很荣幸
- Can I use yours? - Well, that's very flattering,
-但我正忙着 -5678
- but I'm a little busy with -- - 5, 6, 7, 8.
肯定很多人转发 我去发到自己手机上
It's gonna be huge. I'm gonna text it to myself.
好 谢谢
Okay, well, thank you.
进去了 拿上酒
We're in. Bring the wine.
接下来查莉莉 我担心她在吸电子烟
Ooh, do Lily next. I'm worried she's vaping.
爸 你自己坐在这做什么
Dad? What are you doing over here by yourself?
你还好吗
Are you okay?
我担心卢克和曼尼的矛盾
Oh, I'm-I'm worried this Luke and Manny thing
会在工作上影响我和歌洛莉亚
will affect me and Gloria at work.
我们一直相处得很愉快
We've been having such a great time.
我称呼我们为"美女与大佬"
I call us "Chica and the Man."
爸 有件事我必须告诉你
Dad, I have to tell you something.
-告诉他什么 -你是何方神圣
- Tell him what? - How?!
大伙 看看是谁和好了
Hey, everybody, look who's friends again.
没错
That's right.
卢克会和雪莉交往 曼尼不介意了
Luke's gonna date Sherry, Manny's okay.
矛盾解决 农场做派
Problem solved, farm-style!
不好意思
Sorry about that.
在老家 每次有人喊"农场做派"
Back home, when someone would yell "farm-style,"
我们就一起学牛叫
we'd all moo together.
这是良好教养[养殖]的体现
It's a sign of good breeding.
总之 快来 坐好 都坐好
Anyway, come. Sit, sit. Let's go. Sit down.
你还好意思自称哥伦比亚人吗
How do you call yourself Colombian
这么轻易就放过那臭小子
after letting that skunk off the hook so easily?
你最好已经割下他一根脚趾揣兜里了
Tell me, at least, that you have one of his toes in your pocket.
别这样 歌洛莉亚 这是好消息
Come on, now, Gloria. This is good news.
背叛还能被夸是好事吗
Disloyalty being rewarded?
背叛 你真好意思说
Disloyalty? Really?
爸 我撞见歌洛莉亚
Dad, I caught Gloria
找其他房地产经纪人面试工作
interviewing for a job with another Realtor.
什么
What?!
美女 你怎么能这样
Chica! How could you?
她回来了
There she is.
为了躲我从窗户跳出去的女人
The woman that threw herself out the window to avoid me.
爸 别傻了 我是摔出去了
No, Dad. Don't be silly. I-I fell.
不不不 亲爱的 我明白
No, no, no, honey. I get it.
你不想来为我工作
You don't want to come and work for me,
我想我知道为什么
and I think I know why.
爸 我很抱歉
Dad, I'm sorry.
不必 你是不想再次让我失望
No, you don't want to let me down again,
像伊瑟拉视界那个大失误一样
like with that whole... Ezravision fiasco.
什么
What?
不顾别人感受的白人老头
Oh, insensitive old white men.
少了这么一个人圣诞节都不完整了
What would Christmas be without one?
各种肤色的人都会不顾别人感受
We seem to have insensitive people of all ethnicities!
你是在影射我吗 我今天很乖
Was that a shot at me? I've been good.
我忍住没说的话说出来你都不信
You can't believe the stuff I haven't said today.
小卡 你自己回家是怎么回事
Cam, what's up with your trip home?
你父母根本不在老家
Your parents aren't even there.
"圣诞快乐 不是节日快乐
"Merry Christmas. Not Happy Holidays.
来自加尔维斯顿的祝福"
From Galveston."
你怎么查起我的手机了
Okay, how are you snooping through my phone?!
是你
You!
你说录表情包是骗我的
That was a false Boomerang?
你猜怎么着 算了 我原谅你们
Well -- You know what? Forget it. Forgiven.
我只希望今天能是一个特别的圣诞节
I just want today to be a special Christmas.
现在请各位就坐
Now, please, everyone sit down.
我们手拉手祈祷 好好美餐一顿
We'll grab hands, say grace, have a lovely meal.
好了 拉起你们左右两边的手
Okay. Grab the person to your left and right.
亲爱的主
Dear Lord --
我就知道你还因为伊瑟拉视界生气
I knew you were still pissed about that Ezravision thing.
克莱尔 我们在祈祷
Claire, we are praying.
感谢您赐予我们食物
Thank you for this food --
那可是你签字同意的 老伙计
You signed off on that whole deal, buddy!
我才不是因为怕让你失望
And I am not afraid of disappointing you.
感谢您让我们的家人不计较小仇小怨
and for our family as we rise above petty grievances --
是因为新奇狗狗床太蠢了
It's because novelty dog beds are stupid.
狗狗们才不在意它们的床是不是菠萝
Dogs don't care if they're sleeping in a pineapple!
凤梨床在狗众点评网上有四吠好评
The Pina Colassie got four woofs on Whelp!
这话让你听起来像个
That just makes you sound like some --
请求主 让我们不要称呼彼此为
Please, Lord, help us not use terms
"低能"或"傻老头"
like "imbecile" or "senile old man."
我帮你重返职场 你就这样谢我
This is the thanks I get for getting you back into the workplace?
说得好 杰
Nice line, Jay.
这句话原封不动还给你妻子
I could say the same thing to your wife.
真不敢相信你告我的密
I can't believe that you ratted me out.
我才不怕你
I'm not afraid of you!
有这么多人在我就不怕
With... everyone else around.
好了 够了
Okay. That's enough.
真不敢相信你们所有人连一顿饭的工夫
I can't believe you all couldn't hold it together
都必须要吵起来
for one meal and not argue!
小卡 我们每次过节都是这样的
Cam, this is what we always do on the holidays.
有什么大不了的
What's the big deal?
大不了的是
The big deal is that...
这可能是我们最后一次一起过圣诞了
this could be our last Christmas together.
-什么 -最后的圣诞
- What? - Last Christmas?
-少夸张了 -你是什么意思
- Stop being so dramatic. - What do you mean?
我的天 你要死了吗
Oh, my God. You're dying?
不 我不是要死了 是其他的理由
No, I'm not dying. It's something else.
他是故意暂停增加戏剧性吗
Is he pausing to be dramatic?
你新来的吗
What do you think?
-你能不能... -都是从秋天开始的
- Will you j- - It all started last fall.
有个球探来看了我的一场比赛 对我很满意
A scout came to one of my games and liked what he saw,
现在密苏里中北部大学在选总教练
and now I'm one of two finalists for the head coaching position
我是两个最终候选人之一
at the University of North Central Missouri.
-什么 -你是什么意思
- What? - What do you mean?
那可是大事
Hey, that's a big deal.
是的 他们让我飞过去
Yeah, they're flying me out to, uh,
见见体育部主任 假如一切顺利
meet the athletic director, and if all goes well...
开春我就能上任了
I could start this spring.
你为什么没跟我直说
W-Why didn't you just tell me?
因为我不想给你压力
'Cause I-I didn't want to stress you out
想等定了再说
until it was-it was real.
等等
So...wait.
你们真的要搬走吗
W-Would you guys really move?
米奇尔才不会搬去密苏里
Mitchell's not moving to Missouri.
他能做什么工作 起诉小镇酒鬼奥蒂斯吗
What would he do for work? Prosecute Otis, the town drunk?
不好意思 我们不是小县城
Excuse me. It's not Mayberry.
而且告诉你 我们镇上的害群之马
And I'll have you know, our town ne'er-do-well
是吸处方鼻喷上瘾的女性
is a female who's addicted to prescription nasal spray, so...
我还要补充
Okay, and-and-and just for the record, I...
我会去的
I would go.
这样才公平 小卡在这里住了这么久
I mean, it's only fair. Cam's been here forever.
我不喜欢这样
I don't like this.
我知道 大伙
I know, you guys.
但这对他来说是个大机会
But this is an incredible opportunity for him.
我怎么能不同意
How could I say no?
你们不能走
You guys can't go!
我不希望宝宝的生活里没有你们
I don't want my babies growing up without you.
他们永远不会相信我的那些故事
They're never gonna believe my stories!
瞧 所以我才保密
See, this is why I kept it a secret.
我还在这里担心你们毁掉圣诞节
Here I was, worried about you all ruining Christmas,
结果现在被我毁了
and...now I've done it.
大家 我很抱歉
I'm sorry, everyone.
你完全不必抱歉
You have no reason to be sorry.
我很抱歉 我拆散家庭
Yes, I do. I break up families.
像伊丽莎白·泰勒一样
I'm Liz Taylor.
你为什么总是自比女人
Why is it never a man?
既然聊到这了 小卡舅舅
For what it's worth, Uncle Cam,
我的公司在纽约有分部
my company has an office in New York,
我说了我愿意被指派过去
and I said I'd be open to transferring,
说不定我才是拆散家庭的罪人
so I could easily break up the family.
你... 你从没跟我们提过啊
You -- You never mentioned this to us.
对了 我也跟我公司诺普说
Yeah, and I told NERP that I would be
我愿意去巴黎分公司工作
open to working at the Paris office.
迪兰跟我也一直很想去那里住
I mean, Dylan and I have always wanted to live there.
等等
Wait.
你要把双胞胎带去法国吗
Y-You'd take the babies to France?
我们... 我们其实有考虑过这想法
We -- We -- We've talked about it.
抱歉 你们一看着我时我就紧张
Sorry. I get nervous when you're all looking at me.
我也申请了
A-And I applied
伦敦的名校皇家戏剧艺术学院
to the Royal Academy of Dramatic Arts in London.
我也有可能会去那里啊
I could end up there.
对对对 这超"有可能"
Yeah, that's a real possibility.
如果大家都要各奔东西
Listen, if everyone's taking off,
或许我们也可以去棕榈泉买那套房子
maybe we buy that house in Palm Springs,
多多在那里享受人生
spend a little more time there.
意思是明年圣诞节有可能就剩下
And that means next Christmas would be
我与菲尔还有一些可怜的小火腿[猪]吗
me and Phil and some sad little ham?
乔不会跟着外公外婆走吗
Oh, wouldn't Joe go with Grandpa and Gloria?
抱歉 亲爱的 我只是又醉又伤感罢了
Sorry, sweetie. I'm just drunk and upset.
气氛一下就哀伤了起来
This got sad.
好歹现在还没有人要离开嘛
Right. Well, no -- no one's leaving now.
-在还有机会时珍惜并享受彼此的陪伴吧 -对啊
- You know, so let's just enjoy each other while we still can. - Yes!
-对吧 -没错 来帮忙我把沙拉弄好 米奇
- Right? - Yes. Help me with the salads, Mitch.
-好的 没问题 -来吧
- Yes. Okay. - Yes.
我们速速就回
We'll be right back.
菲尔
Phil...
我去那个面试是因为我爱你
I took that interview because I love you,
我不想毁了我们之间的关系
and I don't want to screw up our relationship.
我不想我们最后变成克莱尔与杰
I don't want to end up like Claire and Jay.
你想太多了 我们相处得可开心了
Please. You and I have been doing great.
那是因为我有所保留
Because I hold back.
我其实很有主见
I have strong opinions
但我一直没说出来 因为不想跟你有冲突
that I don't tell you because I want to get along.
什么想法啊
Like what?
有什么想法都可以跟我说啊
You can tell me anything.
比如公交站长椅的广告牌
Like that bus bench sign.
我觉得太傻里傻气了
I think it's goofy.
我们的视力都很好 为什么要戴眼镜啊
If we have 20/20 vision, why are we wearing glasses?
我明白了
I get it.
我只是想要在我国现在这纷纷扰扰之际
I just wanted to bring a little joy to our country
为人民注入一点欢乐气氛 但你不是我国人
in this tumultuous time, but you're not from here,
所以对你来说这点根本无所谓
so maybe it doesn't matter as much to you.
你看你这样子
You see?
我明白了
Yes.
懂了 我很玻璃心
Yes. I'm sensitive.
但我还是需要啊
But I-I need this.
需要一个人可以提出意见来跟我进行智慧的碰撞
New ideas, someone -- someone to push up against me.
说实话 你是这世上
And honestly, I can't think of anyone
我最能接受来跟我碰撞的人了
I'd rather have pushing up against me than you.
菲尔 我忍好多年了
Ay, Phil, it's been years.
我不能再假装没听到你词里的歧义了
I can't pretend I don't hear those anymore.
听到什么
Hear what?
是啦 你说得对
Yeah. You're right.
伊瑟拉视界的事是我自己签的字
I did sign off on that whole... Ezravision thing.
不是你的错
Mm-hmm. It's not your fault.
其实我...
Well, I, uh...
我会有点犟嘴或许是我觉得自己也有责任
I might be a little defensive because I feel responsible.
而狗床的生意... 并不蠢啦
And dog beds aren't -- they're not stupid.
狗狗开心主人就开心嘛 对吧
People are happy when their dogs are happy, right?
我的确是在拯救世界啦
Well, I'm definitely saving lives,
但这生意也是没有一飞冲天[离开橱柜界]
but, I mean, they're not... exactly flying off the shelf.
你是想拖我跟你一起下水吗
You were trying to bring me aboard a sinking ship?
我是想要邀请你来跟我一起拯救它
Well, I was bringing you aboard to -- to save it,
就算你都救不起也没关系 我...
or even if you couldn't, I-I...
我只是很想念跟你一起打拼啦
I just miss working together.
给我一种重新当个好爸爸的机会
I feel it gave me a second chance with you.
有的 真的有 老爸
It did. It did, Dad.
我心里对你无冤无仇了
And we're good now.
所以是时候我该离巢去展翅高飞
So, it's time for me to go and prove myself on my own.
你看看
Look at this.
对我来说 10秒钟前 你也才那么大
10 seconds ago, that was you.
我得确保我跟他不需要第二次机会来修复
I gotta make sure he and I don't need a second chance.
小心啦
Yeah. Well, watch out.
感觉很快他就得去当你的员工了
Pretty soon, he's gonna be working for you.
我不知道他有没有来商界闯荡的头脑
You know, I don't know if he has the head for it.
之前他跟我提了一个猫形状狗床的点子
He pitched a dog bed the other day in the shape of a cat.
谁会想要睡在敌人体内啊
I mean, who wants to sleep in your enemy?
简直像我睡在乔恩·沃伊特体内
It would be like me napping in Jon Voight.
-我跟你说过那个故事吧 -说过了
- I told you that story... - Yeah. Yeah.
看到了吗 你得到你想要的圣诞节
Look at that. You got what you wanted for Christmas.
是的 而且你看 每个人都坐在
Yes, and can I just say, everyone is exactly
我最早安排他们坐的座位上
where I put them in the first place?
过各种节日时 是哪一点令我们情绪脆弱呢
What is it about the holidays that makes us so emotional?
是因为看着孩子们都在长大吗
Is it watching our kids grow up?
谁会赢呢
Who's gonna get it?
还是因为我们能冰释前嫌
Is it how we put our disagreements aside?
等等 如果我们扮演雪儿与桑尼夫妇
What if instead, I am Cher, you are Sonny,
并说出他们乐团的经典歌词"我有[罩]你宝贝"
and it says "We've got you, babe"?
歌洛莉亚 我不知道怎么说了
Gloria, I-I don't know how to say this, but that is
但这真是我听过最他妈新鲜的点子了
the freshest damn idea I have ever heard!
我爱死啦
I love it!
还是因为跟你一生都离不开的人待在一起
Is it just being with people you can't imagine life without?
亲爱的你看
Oh, look, sweetie.
上面写这个密苏里州城市有鲜活的艺术文化
It says that this Missouri town has a lively art scene.
是"方舟文化"
It says "Ark scene."
他们在为下一次神降大洪水做准备
They're preparing for the Lord's next flood?
"有意思"
Fun.
还是...
Or is it --
别闹了 我们能不能好好把照拍完
Enough! Can we just take this picture already?
人家只是想多多珍惜大家齐聚一堂的时光
Excuse me for wanting to cherish you all as long as I can.
工作那边都还没说要你
You don't even have the job yet.
好了 定时拍摄已就绪 15秒倒数
Alright, the timer's set, everyone. We have 15 seconds!
来吧来吧 大家快各就各位
Let's go, everybody. Hurry up.
天啊
Oh, my God.
雪莉跟我分手了
Sherry broke up with me.
在我发给她所有
After I texted her all
你教我的那些好听话之后就说分手了
those nice things you told me to say to her.
对哦 我忘了
Oh, yeah, that's right!
她很讨厌男生发展太快
She hates it when guys move too fast.
爱过但失去 总比爱的资格都没有要强
Oh, well. Better to have loved and lost.
真是我的哥伦比亚乖儿子
There's my Colombian boy!
我回来啦
Hey! I'm back!
你回来啦
Hi!
所以工作单位那边有消息了吗
So, have you heard anything about the job yet?
没 还没呢
No. No, not yet.
而且可能接下来几个月都得等 但...
And I may not for a couple months, but...
我已经尽人事 剩下只能
it's out of my control, and I'm just --
听天命了
I'm letting go.
我要疯啦
This is killing me!
我的未来命悬一线
My whole future hangs in the balance,
而这些人... 他们根本不当回事
and these people... they don't care.
他们根本不在乎
They don't care!
我现在好多了
I'm better now.
既来之则安之
Whatever happens, happends.
快他妈的把我手机还我
Give me my damn phone.
我要打给这些虐待狂
I'm gonna call the sadists,
我要问他们
and I'm gonna ask him,
他们为什么恨我要我死
why they hate me?
管他们的呢
You know what? Screw them.
我喜欢我们的现状
I love what we have.
老天爷对我真好
I'm so blessed.
感觉无论我再怎么努力
It's like no matter what I do,
我永远都只能有个"一半人生"
I'm always gonna have a B+ life.
永远不能圆圆满满
Never an A.
1秒 祝你也新年快乐
And.... Happy new year to you too!